The Papers of Bruce J. Anderson 1950-1988
Roanoke Public Libraries
Roanoke Public Libraries
The Papers of Bruce J. Anderson
Roanoke Public Libraries
2013.07.22
4 record storage boxes
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Bruce J. Anderson
Biographical Note
Bruce J. Anderson of Wytheville, Virginia published the Poindexter Descendants Association Newsletter in the 1980s. His family genealogy is extensively documented. His ancestors are descended from George Poingdestre, an immigrant to the Colony of Virginia in 1657 from the English Channel Isle of Jersey.
Scope and Content
Bruce J. Anderson completed extensive genealogy on his family, which is compiled in this collection. The collection contains correspondence, cards, newsletters, genealogical journals, various family genealogies, unpublished studies, lists of relatives and descendants, rubbings of tombstones, miscellaneous documents, histories, clippings, articles, excerpts from books, and a number of photographs. The bulk of the material was gathered during the 1980s. A few of the documents are photocopies of nineteenth century documents and other published studies of family histories. There is a website for the Poindexter Family Association at http://www.poindexterfamily.org, which documents the history of the American descendants of the Poingdestre Family of Jersey and Normandy. Some of the family names that appear among the materials include: Anderson, Poindexter, Puddister, Pendexter, Poingdestre, Brunner, Brown, Ohlund, Tucker, Crawford, Stray, Simmerly, Martin, Vest, Hartman, Wag, Thomas, George, Archibald and Alexander. Included among the genealogical materials are documents on the Huguenots in general and information about the claims of Cherokee related descendants against the United States government. Original order, as received, was maintained in processing and there are several roughly chronological sequences in the collection. However, the order of the materials is not strictly chronological. To maintain order, series are arranged by family name and provenance as they appeared when the collection was received by the Virginia Room.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by family surnames and topical subdivisions. Original order of the collection was maintained.
Contents List
- Poindexter Family, 1950-1988 (Box 1)
  - Poindexter Family 1950-1987 (Folder 1)
  - Poindexter Family 1971 (Folder 2)
  - Poindexter Family 1962 (Folder 3)
  - Poingdestre Family 1986 (Folder 4)
  - Puddister Family 1986 (Folder 5)
  - Brunner Family 1986 (Folder 6)
  - Poindexter, Photographs 1984-1987 (Folder 7)
  - Pendexter Family 1984-1988 (Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Surnames 1980-1988 (Folder 9)
  - Ed Terry Correspondence 1980-1982 (Folder 10)
  - Tennessee Cousins 1980-1988 (Folder 11)
  - Dames of Magna Carther unknown (Folder 12)
  - R.B. Taylor Correspondence 1985-1986 (Folder 13)
  - Poindexter Descendants Association 1986 (Folder 14)
  - Dorothy Knox Brown Correspondence 1985-1987 (Folder 15)
  - Doucette, Texas 1984-1987 (Folder 16)
  - Ray Tucker Correspondence 1987 (Folder 17)
  - Florence Ohland Correspondence 1982-1984 (Folder 18)
  - Bruce Anderson Correspondence 1977 (Folder 19)
  - Bruce Anderson Correspondence 1976-1977 (Folder 20)
  - Bruce Anderson Correspondence 1977 (Folder 21)
  - Poindexter File 1965 (Folder 22)
  - American Family Records Association Correspondence 1982 (Folder 23)
  - American Family Records Association Correspondence 1982-1983 (Folder 24)
  - American Family Records Association Journal 1983 (Folder 25)
  - American Family Records Association Journal 1984 (Folder 26)
  - American Family Records Association Journal 1985-1986 (Folder 27)
  - Bruce Anderson Correspondence and Miscellaneous Documents 1971 (Folder 28)
  - Poindexter Genealogy and Miscellaneous Documents 1981 (Folder 29)
  - Brevard County Historical Book, 1820-1920 1982 (Folder 30)
  - Hardees: A Brevard County Florida History undated (Folder 31)
- Poindexter Family, 1930-1988 (Box 2)
  - John Stray Correspondence 1987 (Folder 1)
  - Family Reunions 1984-1985 (Folder 2)
  - Genealogy in General 1974-1987 (Folder 3)
  - Josephine Simmerly Correspondence 1984 (Folder 4)
  - Hildrus Poindexter 1980-1988 (Folder 5)
  - Flossie Martin 1980-1988 (Folder 6)
  - Vest Family 1980-1988 (Folder 7)
  - Hartman Family 1980-1988 (Folder 8)
  - Shreveport, Lousiana 1980-1988 (Folder 9)
  - Cherokee Claims 1972/1984 (Folder 10)
  - Admiral Poindexter 1980-1988 (Folder 11)
  - Huguenots 1987 (Folder 12)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution 1930-1980 (Folder 13)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution 1930-1980 (Folder 14)
  - Poindexter Family 1980-1988 (Folder 15)
  - Poindexters of North Carolina 1970-1979 (Folder 16)
  - Thomas Poindexter 1970-1979 (Folder 17)
  - Francis Poindexter 1970-1979 (Folder 18)
  - Wag Poindexter 1970-1979 (Folder 19)
  - Thomas Poindexter 1970-1979 (Folder 20)
  - John George Poindexter 1970-1979 (Folder 21)
  - Archibald Poindexter 1970-1979 (Folder 22)
  - Robert Alexander Poindexter 1970-1979 (Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous 1970-1979 (Folder 24)
  - Poindexter Family 1981 (Folder 25)
  - Early Elkin, Jonesville 1981 (Folder 26)
  - Poindexter-Crawford Family 1981 (Folder 27)
  - Saco Valley Settlements and Families 1987 (Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Genealogical Repositories 1 1980-1988 (Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Genealogical Repositories 2 1980-1988 (Folder 30)
  - Tennessee Poindexter Source Materials 1970-1979 (Folder 31)
  - Poindexter Graveyard Data 1980-1988 (Folder 32)
  - Poindexter Eastern Cherokee Claims 1980-1988 (Folder 33-38)
- Poindexter Family, 1970-1988 (Box 3)
  - Poindexter Eastern Cherokee Claims 1980-1988 (Folder 1-5)
  - Poindexter Files 1986 (Folder 6-7)
  - Poindexter Files 1970-1979 (Folder 8-10)
  - Poindexter Files 1970-1988 (Folder 11-12)
  - John Stray Poindexter 1980-1988 (Folder 13)
  - John Stray Poindexter, Photographs 1980-1988 (Folder 14)
  - Poindexter File 1979 (Folder 15)
  - Poingdestre Genealogy 1986 (Folder 16)
  - Poindexter References 1970-1988 (Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous 1980-1988 (Folder 18)
  - Poindexter File 1984 (Folder 19-22)
  - Poindexter File 1987 (Folder 23-24)
  - Poindexter File 1980 (Folder 25)
  - Poindexter File 1982 (Folder 26)
  - Poindexter File 1983 (Folder 27)
- Poindexter Family, 1970-1988 (Box 4)
  - Poindexter Miscellaneous Notes 1970-1979 (Folder 1)
  - Source Materials for North Carolina Poindexters 1970-1979 (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Genealogical Sources 1970-1979 (Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Genealogical Sources 1970-1988 (Folder 4-7)
  - Miscellaneous Genealogical Sources undated (Folder 8)
  - Ancestry Charts 1980-1988 (Folder 9-11)
  - Cherokee Claims/Applications undated (Folder 12)
  - Virginia Poindexters 1980-1988 (Folder 13-15)